Patrick O'Shea

Email: pcoshea2@gmail.com

Github: github.com/posheadig

Website: patrickoshea.art **Social**: patrick_oshea

I am a consultant, technologist, and artist. My work seeks to explore the socio-technical systems that underpin our societal structures and environmental interactions. I've been involved in numerous international projects with a focus on environmental science, cultural heritage, and the development of critical research frameworks. My active participation in open-source development aims to foster community engagement while enhancing the accessibility, value, and adaptability of open-access research frameworks.

Experience

2023-2024 **R&D**

Open Value, Web3

2021 - 2023 Principal Researcher / Senior Product Manager / Senior Data Engineer

Agora Labs, Web3

2020 - 2021 Guest Researcher

Land Arts of the American West: Texas Tech University, Lubbock, TX

2015-Present **Freelance Consultant**

Software development, COP26 ethnography, writing, project management, geomorphology technician, archaeology technician, design, fabrication.

Education

2018 - 2020 MFA, Technology Studies

School of the Art Institute of Chicago, Chicago, IL

Awarded the New Artist Society Full Merit fellowship and student leadership award.

2007 - 2015 **BA, Anthropology**

University of Vermont, Burlington, VT

Teaching & Workshops

- 3/1/2024 Brooklyn Arts Cluster, Workshop titled 'decentralized tech as research tools'
- 2023 China Academy of Fine Arts, Visiting Professor of Al and data ethics

- 11/01/2022 Shanghai University, Workshop on Web3 Theory & Technologies
- 04/01/2022 Ohio State University, Workshop on GIS and mapping data ethics
- 2021 Glasgow School of Art, COP26: Into the Oceanic
- 2018-2020 School of the Art Institute of Chicago, TA

Exhibitions

- 2024 Brooklyn Arts Cluster, Reverse TarPit, NY
- 2023 The Wrong Biennale NYC Onassis ONX Studio @ New Art City
- 2021 The Fish Hotel / Chemical [Re] Actions, Goethe Institute of Chicago
- 2020 [co-curator / exhibitor] Ars Electronica Digital Gardens, Linz Austria/Virtual
- 2020 The Future of Our Plans, SAIC Virtual
- 2020 Messages from the Anthropocene, Flynndog Gallery, Burlington VT
- 2019 NØ Exhibition, Nevers, France
- 2019 Future Conditions, SAIC, Chicago IL
- 2017 New City Gallery, Burlington VT

Publications

- 2022 [co-author] Land Arts of the American West Publication in Zoe Leonard Al Rio / To the River, HATJE CANTZ/MUDAM LUXEMBOURG
- 2022 "Collectivity + Collaboration" Southwest Contemporary Vol. 5, March 2022.